Today we'll talk about access points to children.
Now, of course there are a lot of
access points, but the focus is about technology
access points to children.
If you listen to me to the end,
I want to share a personal experience that
affected me for a long time, and this
was because of the access that I had
in my early stage.
But before we even do that, what is
really access points?
In the technology term, access points are a
combination of computers connected together within a location.
Yes, our children are connected together these days,
even beyond what we know.
But the question is that, as parents, what
are we doing to really understand some of
the access points that technology already created to
these children?
Having this understanding will give you some level
of advantage on how to leverage and monitor
these children.
Technology comes with some disadvantage.
If there's anything I want you to take
away from this video today is that technology
is the greatest access point to children today.
And as parents, what can we do to
ensure that this access point is safe and
unique to our children?
Yes, there's no longer news about when we
hear the term children are addicted to screen.
It is real.
But rather than we fighting them being addicted
to screen, I think the bottom line now
is what are the things that we can
do in such a way that even when
they are on their screen, they are doing
something meaningful and something that will even yield
more results in their academics.
These are ways that we should start thinking
as parents.
Rather than just fighting them and, you know,
telling them to leave the screen, we can
take advantage of what the screen has to
offer.
Experts say that technology offers more potential to
children only if parents are able to monitor
them.
The question today is how intense are you
monitoring your children?
And there are ways you can monitor your
children that it becomes a problem, especially when
they feel that you're going to be preventing
them from exploring what they want to do.
At that point, they hide so many things
without you really knowing.
Because whether you like it or not, you
give them device to use.
No matter how you monitor that device, there's
always a way for them to do something
that they are not supposed to be doing.
Unless you want to say for the sake
of it, you've put all the measures in
place in the device you hand over to
them.
One thing that is also very common is
that you're not sure or you can't control
the kind of devices that will be exposed
to them when they are not with you.
And that leads us to my story when
I was in secondary school.
When I was in secondary school, I happened
to like a computer lab very well because
then the government were able to purchase some
notebooks that we could use to browse the
internet.
And things were very, very fun at that
time as well.
Well, the challenge here is that we had
access to the internet, but there were no
restrictions.
There were no intense restriction and there were
no guidelines on what to be done and
what shouldn't be done.
So these were just vulnerable kids going to
the internet and doing all manner of things.
There's this fateful day I would never forget.
This is my friend just walking to the
computer lab and he said, let me show
you something.
And I was like, what do you want
to show me?
The guy just, you know, took the notepad
from me and he just typed the URL
into the notebook and boom, when the page
loads, it happens to be adult videos that
came up.
Now, of course, as children, as I saw
it, I was, I kept looking, I kept
staring at it and I crammed the URL.
I can tell you for free that till
today, I still know that exact website that
that's my friend introduced me to.
And beyond that, I also visited the website
multiple times and it took the help of
God to help me through that.
These are the kind of access point I'm
talking about.
Negative access points that will become a dent
in a child's life, even when they are
grown.
This is really not to scare you, not
at all.
This is just an avenue to let you
know that as parents, it is very important
for us to understand that there are access
points.
Our job is ensuring that our children are
not exposed negatively to this access point.
And my hack ever since then is that
when somebody say, let me show you something.
First and foremost, I will ask the person,
what is that that you want to show
me?
If you cannot explain it to me clearly,
then I will not allow you to show
me.
If I had been told all of those
tips earlier on, I won't see that adult
website that my friend introduced me to.
Right.
And these are some of the informations as
parents that we need to know.
Some tips, some guidance, some inspirations that we
need to just provide to our children in
order for them not to make mistakes.
Now let's face the truth.
One mistake that parents make is enroling their
kids in numerous programmes thinking that's all.
For example, you see one coding programme, you
enrol your child and you think that's all.
That's really not all.
There is something about going through the journey
with them.
The same way if your child wants to
become a footballer, that you follow the child
to the training ground, learn how some of
those things work, help the child to train
on their own.
It works similarly on the internet and on
the cyberspace as well.
So one thing you can do as parents
is ensure that you also understand how some
of these things work.
By understanding how some of these things work,
you realise that the conversation between you and
your child will sink along the way.
This is the reason why we are introducing
summer coding class every year.
And with summer coding class, we not only
introduce children to how technology works.
After we engage children for five solid weeks,
in week six, the children will showcase whatever
they've learned, demo everything to their parents to
see.
Guess what happened during that time?
Parents also get to learn how some of
these things work.
Parents get to have conversations with their children,
how some of this technology works.
So I want you to be part of
the summer coding class this year.
I want your child to experience what it
means to use technology ethically, get exposed to
how technology has been built, demonstrate and communicate
all of those things effectively.
If you're interested, all you need to do
is to hit the link attached to the
video description and let's get started with the
conversation.
One more thing, you're watching this video and
this is helpful to you and you're here
to follow us on all our social media.
First, you need to like and subscribe to
this video, then follow us on all our
social media platforms so that you can be
notified every time we release a new tip.
Until next time, I'll see you in the
next one.